<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>meta on Quentin Baker</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/tags/meta/</link><description>Quentin Baker (meta)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 21:57:27 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.quentb.com/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introductions</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/posts/introductions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 21:57:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.quentb.com/posts/introductions/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-new-new-new-new-blog">A new new new (new?) Blog
&lt;span>&lt;a href="#a-new-new-new-new-blog">#&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Randall Munroe, among others, has noted the chronic problem of content producers who can&amp;rsquo;t commit.
&lt;img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/superlative.png" alt="xkcd comic #621" title="Stay while I recount the crazy TF2 kill I managed
yesterday, my friends.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not going to try and promise I&amp;rsquo;ll post a lot, or even that this blog won&amp;rsquo;t go stale, disappear, and maybe be
replaced by yet another in 2 years &amp;ndash; history shows this is likely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do hope you find something interesting here that tickles your mind and causes you to stop and ponder, if only for a
moment. In times like these, that is a great accomplishment for writers; now we have to fight for your attention with
literally the entire world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you are reading this, thank you. You could be watching cat videos, Minecraft let&amp;rsquo;s plays, or doom-scrolling your
&lt;del>drug&lt;/del> social media feed of choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, in brief, is what I&amp;rsquo;d like to offer you. If you think that any of this sounds interesting, I invite you to
bookmark this site, subscribe to the RSS feed (yes those still exist) or just set a calendar event a couple months out
to &amp;ldquo;go see what Quentin wrote, if anything&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="while-supplies-last">While Supplies Last
&lt;span>&lt;a href="#while-supplies-last">#&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>On this blog, I will write about the utterly, painfully mundane. I may write about trying to color match the carpet in my
apartment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will write about technology. Its in my nature to buzz around the newest gadgets like a moth around lamps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will probably write a few semi-serious reviews of stuff. This may be books, my newest headphones, my car, or the local
asphalt conditions. Practicing distilling an opinion into something presentable is a worthwhile endeavor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will more than likely complain or obsess over language. Upfront, I will state: I am pro-oxford-comma, I think split
infinitives are fine, and in my opinion you are almost certainly over-using adverbs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will vent. Its like writing a diary, but with the added excitement of cutting-edge global networks taking the hassle
out of the old-school &amp;ldquo;sneaking into my room while I&amp;rsquo;m distracted, finding the journal, and trying to giggle silently&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the best,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quentin&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>