<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>review on Quentin Baker</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/tags/review/</link><description>Recent content in review on Quentin Baker</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Quentin Baker</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.quentb.com/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Review: Architecture of Happiness</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/arch-of-happiness-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/arch-of-happiness-review/</guid><description>Nota bene: This is a post manually carried forward from an older iteration of my blog. It may not match the tone or topic of my more recent posts.
Remembering Who We Are: A Review of The Architecture of Happiness In The Architecture of Happiness, by Alain de Botton, the reader may find several different books intertwined: A cursory glance finds a historic overview of Architecture and its changing sensibilities, while a thorough reading reveals additional forays from the authors point of view as they walk with us through their personal discovery of what they find appealing or disconcerting about the buildings they encounter around the world.</description></item><item><title>Haiku In English: A Review</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/haiku-anthology-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/haiku-anthology-review/</guid><description>Nota bene: This is a post manually carried forward from an older iteration of my blog. It may not match the tone or topic of my more recent posts.
I don’t know if anyone in the history of written language has ever, on their own volition, gone out to a bookstore and bought themselves a book of Haikus. I know I haven’t. In my case, I received Haiku in English: The first Hundred Years as a Christmas present a few years ago and only then because my parents knew one of the Editors, Mr.</description></item></channel></rss>