<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>old-blog on Quentin Baker</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/tags/old-blog/</link><description>Quentin Baker (old-blog)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.quentb.com/tags/old-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving out and Losing Keys</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/losing-keys/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/losing-keys/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Nota bene: This is a post manually carried forward from an older iteration of my blog. It may not match the tone or
topic of my more recent posts.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you ever stopped to consider how much we put behind locks? The past 48 hours has been nothing but that thought
running through my mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I normally like airports. I always have had an affinity to these massive buildings designed for such a singular goal:
take as many humans as possible, with all their accoutrements, put them on airplanes and send them off. In a space where
the architecture itself is made to get you to move, to leave, I find myself pausing anyway. There is a promise of
hundreds of possible futures, one behind each gate. Sure, I’ve got a ticket taking me back home, but what if I tore it
up, bought a ticket to Europe, and never looked back?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its a sort of “call of the void”, a voice that whispers to you when standing at the edge of a canyon, saying “jump!” A
sane person never does, but surely everyone has wondered. I get a sort of contact high just running the possibility
through my mind, and its this wonder, this possibility, that permeates and overpowers any dullness in air travel for me,
no matter how often I fly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suppose the universe has some mechanism by which it occasionally steps in and flings that sense of enjoyment in the
gutter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I landed back in Grand Rapids at 9:48 PM, ready to drive home and sleep in my own bed once more. I’d just returned from
a lovely wedding in Colorado, but now the bride and groom were off to Maine, the guests had long since sloughed off
jackets and dresses, and the everlasting moment of joy was quickly fading into another warm memory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was time to return to the normal rhythm of things. Having just graduated college, this pattern of life wears on my
soul like some new pair of shoes. I know it won’t be long before things have stretched and compressed until life feels
“regular”, but right now I was tasting the irregularity of regular.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No more late-night study sessions. No summer vacation. The weekend parties and spontaneous gatherings have dwindled. On
the other hand, no looming unexpected deadlines, no juggling 5 different subjects, and no agonizing over the search for
employment. I recall a thought flashing through my mind as I walked out of the jetway Monday night, “I hope this isn’t
all there is from now on.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The baggage terminal carousel is broken. A tired, harried fellow in an airline vest tries to get everyone’s attention,
asking for our patience. It takes another half an hour before we see our belongings. I remembered my unspoken wish for
future change and bitterly chuckled at myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the economy lot, I stepped off the shuttle last. Ahead sat my car, an aging Buick that has been passed around my
family like an unwanted holiday fruit cake. I don’t mind it, though. It runs well and has comfortable seats. Sure, the
breaks squeal, and after a side-swipe in January the door doesn’t close all the way, but it went from A to B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My hand slipped into my pocket for my keys, and instead of a jingle of metal and plastic, felt nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me tell you, I was not enjoying airports while I had my belongings strewn across the asphalt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing. They weren’t there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I called home. Maybe I left them downstairs where I packed? While I anxiously listened over the phone, Mom methodically
turned the house inside out, and came up empty. Darkness was over the land.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ended up phoning a local friend and crashed at his place that night. In the morning, I called into work and told
everyone I was going to be remote for the day. Via text, phone, and email we widened the search radius from the house,
to the cars, to the different cities we’d stopped in over my long weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe its silly, but some hours into this frustrating search I remembered the Sunday sermon, delivered by a guest pastor
to my parents’ congregation. It focused on the end of the book of Job. At first I chided myself for the thought that I
was like Job, a man who loses literally everything he had on earth, including his health. It’s just some silly keys, no
need to sit in the ashes yet, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had no car. If I could somehow get home, I couldn’t get in to my apartment. Less than 24 hours ago I had been
explaining to friends how I “finally felt like an Adult”. In this moment, despite knowing better, I felt like Job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything is a swirling mess right now. I’m sitting on a friend’s couch in my last pair of clean clothing as I type
this, but my storm is already calming. I’m figuring out the next steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been thinking, everyone has a key chain of important stuff. Sure, literal collections of keys are in there, but its
more than that. I’m watching family members who are facing an unexpected wall where they thought they had a career. I’m
seeing parents grow older and the invincible aura they had when I was a child wane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m wondering what I’m going to do when I find or replace all my keys. What lesson is being taught here in this short,
intense period of life disruption? I guess we can’t find out while in the middle of the storm. Perhaps its time for me
to get my head out of the clouds and hunker down the next time I pass through an airport, checking off my list of
belongings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe I need to be more presentable. I have been simultaneously warned not to hide myself and not to share too much
recently. I feel intensely lonely yet claustrophobic. I am afraid of looking up in twenty, thirty, forty years and
seeing a winding trail of meaninglessness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did all this really come from losing a stupid collection of cut metal and plastic? Just once in my life I want to have
grand revelations from God delivered the good old fashioned, Old Testament way, so the world outside my head can look as
crazy as the inside.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Architecture of Happiness</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/arch-of-happiness-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/arch-of-happiness-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Nota bene: This is a post manually carried forward from an older iteration of my blog. It may not match the tone or
topic of my more recent posts.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="remembering-who-we-are-a-review-of-the-architecture-of-happiness">Remembering Who We Are: A Review of The Architecture of Happiness&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In &lt;em>The Architecture of Happiness&lt;/em>, by Alain de Botton, the reader may find several different books intertwined: A cursory glance finds a historic overview of Architecture and its changing sensibilities, while a thorough reading reveals additional forays from the authors point of view as they walk with us through their personal discovery of what they find appealing or disconcerting about the buildings they encounter around the world. Both stories ring true, each contributing to a larger goal, a plea from the author:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We owe it to the fields that our houses will not be inferiors of the virgin land they have replaced. We owe it to the worms and the trees that the buildings we cover them in will stand as promises of the highest and most intelligent kinds of happiness.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This book is a short read but carries a heavy weight. De Botton uses concrete examples and personal story to introduce and apply architecture in a way the average reader can take in, resulting in an effective book that I recommend any interested party read. The title of this book can be understood in a few ways: first, one might read it as a suggestion that there is a single best way to display happiness in architecture: that there exists The Architecture of happiness. A better interpretation, I think is found in emphasizing the second word, to read the Architecture of happiness. In this interpretation, De Botton may instead be looking into the framing and structuring of happiness itself. This latter idea is supported from the book:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To describe a building as beautiful therefore suggests more than a mere aesthetic fondness; it implies an attraction to the particular way of life this structure is promoting through its roof, door handles, window frames, staircase and furnishings.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Here the author is using architecture to transcend the physical and move into a metaphysical idea of what buildings provide, and in some ways plays with the idea that truly great architecture has something like a personality, a soul, in which people find resonance. This concept of the soul is further brought into relief by the frank discussion of Architecture as a tool to further ideologies. Though I do not know the author’s faith, his words show an acknowledgement of the power of religious buildings and the effect on any mortal that stands inside, say, a cathedral. Here the author uses a personal story to relay the point. He recalls a time he stopped for a bite at a McDonald’s next to Westminster Cathedral. Inside the restaurant, he found isolation and alienation: “Customers were eating alone, reading papers or staring at the brown tiles, masticating with a sternness and brusqueness beside which the atmosphere of a feeding shed would have appeared convivial and mannered.” After this sapping experience, the Author stepped out of the restaurant and ventured into the Cathedral, where the universe proceeded to shift 180 degrees: “In the presence of alabaster statues of the Virgin Mary set against rhythms of red, green and blue marble, it was no longer surprising to think that an angel might at any moment choose to descend through the layers of dense London cumulus, enter through a window in the nave, blow a golden trumpet and make an announcement in Latin about a forthcoming celestial event.” At the end of this story and this chapter, Alain drops his high-flying diction to provide a powerfully simple summation of the lesson found in his story: “A beautiful building could reinforce our resolve to be good.” As the physical body lives from the oxygen around it, so the mental self breathes in the muse poured out into the world it can sense. In addition to reflections on the impact of Architecture on the person, the author takes time to consider society’s interaction with Architecture. When constructs have such an effect on a person, it would suggest that there is a more effective and less effective style, perhaps a “perfect” style to be derived and codified; then we will all use that style forever and live happily ever after… But this is obviously not so. The style of the day, the author argues, arises as a counterbalance to the pendulum of societal norms:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>…we are drawn to call something beautiful whenever we detect that it contains in a concentrated form those qualities in which we personally, or our societies more generally, are deficient.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This would explain the emergence of neoclassicism and its successor, romanticism. In each phase, the style emerges as a sort of retort to the previous popular style. In architecture, gothic style replaces classical, which in turn is usurped by Victorian, and so on. The author takes this idea back to discuss the problem of, “the two great dogmas of aesthetics: the view that there is only one acceptable visual style or (even more implausibly) that all styles are equally valid.” In returning to the book’s main idea, the reader is provided with the idea that there is a “perfect” style to reflect or balance a given individual’s inner needs. And, given that there are 7 billion humans, that suggests there are likely around 7 billion perfect ideas of architecture.&lt;br>
As the book comes to a close, the author spends some words on the virtues of buildings. Particular emphasis is laid on the everyday dwellings and spaces we inhabit, the spaces that ironically receive the smaller portion of architectural scrutiny. Though the immediate reaction is to believe a more concerted focus is needed, Alain comes to the conclusion that a little mundane, a healthy side of normalcy, is in fact the best course for these spaces. He writes, “The architects who benefit us most may be those generous enough to lay aside their claims to genius in order to devote themselves to assembling graceful but predominantly unoriginal boxes. Architecture should have the confidence and the kindness to be a little boring.”&lt;br>
This book is not without its faults. To be frank, a book that seems aimed toward an architectural novice might be better with a less flowery diction. I found particular irony in the author’s use of the word “grandiloquence”, which is defined as “The use of lofty words or phrases; bombast; —usually in a bad sense.” That said, when the author decides to bring a point home, he generally does so with a simple and powerful summation, one that seems to land on just the right words and phrasing, which is commendable. As Mark Twain wrote: “The difference between the almost right word and the right word is really a large matter. ’tis the difference between the lightning bug and the lightning”. For me, the greatest of these examples in the book comes right at the beginning, when the author writes about a house, “Over the years, its owners have returned from periods away and, on looking around them, remembered who they were.” Bam. That right there holds the best encapsulation of the living breathing beast that Alain argues architecture can be—a beast that devours, or a mighty steed that rushes its rider faster than any man could hope to run. The latter is an exchange between object and person, the person led to interact with, rather than passively admire.&lt;br>
I can’t find where I read it, but one internet review described this book as “a come-to-Jesus moment for architecture.” I read Alain’s gospel, and I will spread the good news: read this book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku In English: A Review</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/haiku-anthology-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.quentb.com/old_blog/haiku-anthology-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Nota bene: This is a post manually carried forward from an older iteration of my blog. It may not match the tone or
topic of my more recent posts.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know if anyone in the history of written language has ever, on their own volition, gone out to a bookstore and
bought themselves a book of Haikus. I know I haven’t. In my case, I received &lt;a href="https://read.amazon.com/kp/embed?asin=B00AR3558C&amp;amp;preview=newtab&amp;amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_KaFpAb7V3247S">&lt;em>Haiku in English: The first Hundred
Years&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
as a Christmas present a few years ago and only then because my parents knew one of the Editors, Mr. Allan Burns. That
said, when I decided to pick up this book out of boredom and flip through it, I found myself surprised at the
cohesiveness, varied selection, and overall enjoyment factor this book contained.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Editors in their foreword note that they sought to introduce a novice haiku reader (that’s what, 99.99% of the
population?) to the evolution and accomplishments of Haiku over the past 100 years. This means a couple of things:
First, that the authors are not listed in alphabetical order, but rather loosely chronologically. The editors also
purposefully start with more traditional examples of a haiku, for example, a selection from Richard Wright:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The sudden thunder&lt;br>
Startles the Magnolias&lt;br>
To a deeper white.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But then quickly move to more abstract, loosely haiku-form poems, or even “eye-kus”, visually short poems that seek to
achieve the same result as a standard three-line version. I personally found the following from Shawn McMurtagh to be a
good example:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/_CfGSxRAFcMA/TFCpUG3E-qI/AAAAAAAABtg/7GHh7DK3oLE/s1600/McMurtagh013.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The poems range from serious to silly; deeply distilled to seemingly spur-of-the moment. Jack Kerouac has an almost
irreverent contribution:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Missing a kick&lt;br>
at the icebox door&lt;br>
It closed anyway&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And Nick Virgilio has a real gut-punch:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>the sack of kittens&lt;br>
sinking in the icy creek&lt;br>
increases the cold&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The poems can jump from one of these states to the other, giving the reader mental whiplash. Then again, perhaps that’s
the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last third or so of the book is devoted to notes and credits, but a short overview of English haikus is also
included here. After finishing with a Haiku from Rebecca Lilly (Snow at dawn… / dead singers in their prime / on the
radio), the editors chose to include a short haiku primer. It starts by noting that, as with so much of our western
borrowed culture, we got the name wrong! Haiku actually comes from the Japanese &lt;em>hokku&lt;/em>, which itself is merely a small
part of a larger collaborative poem style called &lt;em>renga&lt;/em>. With those nitpicks out of the way, a brief coverage of the
formation of the English style commences, including why we have the most common 5-7-5 syllable structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Immediately after this primer is a brief history of the English haiku. Initially, it began with translations of existing
Japanese poems, meaning the West’s first exposure to Haikus was not at the hand of poets, but scholars. Many translators
and scholars started by attempting to bring the original structure and flow of the Japanese poems to English, with
varying success. Finally, Yone Noguchi wrote the first confirmed original English haiku in 1902:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tell me the street to Heaven.&lt;br>
This? Or that? Oh, which?&lt;br>
What webs of streets!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The rest of the history is legitimately interesting and varied, and notes the fingerprints of several generations on the
decidedly different form of the modern English haiku from its Japanese ancestor. Each new group of authors and poets
found the form and left their mark on it. From the first wave, to the “beats” at the end of the ‘30s, and on to the
proliferation of Haiku journals and societies that codified certain aspects of the Haiku, the short form takes on a
complex set of historical overtones, almost as if the form were a fine wine or a particularly stinky aged cheese.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I admit, I did not think this book would be enjoyable. I picked it up expecting a read-through that would be
invigorating as Webster’s New World Dictionary. However, by the end of my journey through this small Anthology, I had a
changed opinion. The poems are genuinely interesting, often thought-provoking, and occasionally could move me to
emotion. Jim Kacian, Philip Rowland, and Allan Burns have produced a wonderful and elegant foray into a world of poetry
I expect most English readers don’t know exist. To sum up:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Haiku in English&lt;br>
Brought from Eastern History&lt;br>
Now in Western Clothes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>-Quentin Baker&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This was a Review of&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://read.amazon.com/kp/embed?asin=B00AR3558C&amp;amp;preview=newtab&amp;amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_KaFpAb7V3247S">Haiku In English: The First One Hundred
Years&lt;/a>,
&lt;em>originally written for a writing class.&lt;/em> &lt;em>I have not met the editors and I have no commercial stake in this book. I
apologize in advance for publishing a review of a Haiku Anthology.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>