<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mental health on Quentin Baker</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/tags/mental-health/</link><description>Quentin Baker (mental health)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 14:31:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.quentb.com/tags/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An Interesting God</title><link>https://www.quentb.com/posts/an-interesting-god/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 14:31:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.quentb.com/posts/an-interesting-god/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have continued my journey, and I wanted to give a bit of an update.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things still feel like I walk in two worlds &amp;ndash; maybe that&amp;rsquo;s my current &amp;ldquo;theme&amp;rdquo;. I like themes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I picked a few &amp;ldquo;annual themes&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NVGuFdX5guE">as suggested by CGP Grey&lt;/a> this year, and they were the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Personal Health&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moderation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Variety&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d check in on what those themes have led me to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="personal-health" >Personal Health
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#personal-health">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>In July 2021, I weighed in at 308 lbs according to my doctors notes. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m in the ballpark of 230. That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty nice move, and I have seen its affects personally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its only since about July that &lt;em>other&lt;/em> people have also noticed, and its generally people I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen in quite a bit of time: moral of the story &amp;ndash; take a look at your old photos. You may not notice yourself, but change is possible, and it does happen!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have walked this path by focusing first on diet, and then on exercise. I&amp;rsquo;m not doing anything particularly impressive for diet currently, and I think it has caused my weight loss to slow. But I now know I can do it, and I&amp;rsquo;m perfectly happy taking a bit longer, as long as it continues to progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its helped my self-esteem quite a bit; I now suspect I&amp;rsquo;m at least a &lt;em>little&lt;/em> handsome. We will see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="moderation" >Moderation
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#moderation">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Tough one to nail down. I actually think of everything this is the most &amp;ldquo;mixed bag&amp;rdquo;. I was thrust into a deep period of inner turmoil this year, starting in April.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I&amp;rsquo;m mostly through it&amp;hellip; but it started as a result of several very long days when I got myself involved in reddit&amp;rsquo;s r/place project. I think the lack of sleep, the emotional high of working on an (admittedly very silly) big team project followed by a crash (my sleep schedule did not fare well for those three or four days) caused me to have a personal moment of &amp;ldquo;what am I doing!?&amp;rdquo; that forced to the surface some big questions I had quite effectively buried for a few years; questions all revolving around my sexuality and my faith. Those deserve there own dedicated post, and I have hope that my mental fortitude will continue improving to a point where I can honestly and frankly discuss them sooner than later.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="variety" >Variety
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#variety">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Well, the mental health crises was actually a pretty good kick in the shorts for this one. I&amp;rsquo;m reading a lot again for the first time in a good long while. I am reading both for fun (Terry Pratchett&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Discworld&lt;/em> series, Jim Butcher&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Dresden Files&lt;/em>, and I hope to start the insane list comprised of Brandon Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s work before the end of the year), and for&amp;hellip; less fun (Seneca, Nietzsche, Kierkegaard, The Bible, Richard Rohr, Rob Bell, John Piper, etc. A lot of philosophy, history, and theology).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think my life in general is more varied, too. I visit more places, I live in a more interesting place, and I am purposefully taking the &amp;ldquo;leap&amp;rdquo; of reaching out and connecting with groups of people with shared interests. This included a very interesting day in Detroit, bowling with a group of Furries.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I have been listening to a lot of different stuff, too. I recently was listening to a religious podcast, and the guest talked about the importance of cultivating a sense of Christ&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;interestingness&amp;rdquo;. I am praying for a few things (including the very basic prayer of &amp;lsquo;Lord Christ, teach me &lt;em>what&lt;/em> to pray for&amp;rsquo;) but I think I will add to my list this, &amp;ldquo;Lord, help me to find the Christ &lt;em>interesting&lt;/em> again.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will see. Thankfully, I am at a place where I can finally take a bit of a breath and stand up to honestly and without fear consider some of these important questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We make terrible judgments when fearful, tired, or anxious, and I believe that if God is just and Loving, he will help us find a path to him that is genuinely a result of interest, excitement, and love, and not mere fear. Fear can be part of the journey, even a fear of God, but it is no basis for a healthy, thriving relationship. I think that is something missed by the people who show up to Pride parades with signs declaring the imminent damnation of the participants.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>